A Guide to the Strong Family Papers, 1823-1855
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Strong Family Papers, 1823-1855
The Library of Virginia
29587
33 pages
Strong Family
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchased, 12 August 1977, from the Bookworm and Silverfish, Wytheville, Virginia.
Biographical Information
The Strongs were a prominent family in Scott County, Virginia. Thomas Strong (ca. 1778-1858) and Samuel Strong (ca. 1808-1863) were apparently father and son.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1823-1855, of the Strong family of Scott County, Virginia, consisting of deeds, 1826-1855, for land in Scott County and in Sullivan County, Tennessee: writ, [October 1823] issued by the Rowan County, North Carolina, Superior Court of Law against Levi Reed of Davidson County, North Carolina, ordering him to pay court costs in the suit between him and John Johnston; receipt, 4 March 1844, for payment for 560 acres in Logan County, Kentucky from George W. Norton to William Summers; writ, 29 May 1845, issued by the Logan County Circuit Court ordering payment of court costs and fees incurred by conviction of Benjamin Townsend and others to the Bank of Kentucky; and title bond, 10 November 1850, for sale of 300 acres in Washington County, Virginia, from Ota H. Ward to Francis Hogzden.
Contents List
- Writ, [October 1823], issued by the Rowan County, North Carolina, Superior Court of Law against Levi Reed of Davidson County, North Carolina, ordering him to pay court costs in the suit between him and John Johnston.
- Deed, dated and recorded 27 July 1826, for 38 acres in Scott County, Virginia, from Henry Peters to William L. Dulaney.
- Deed, dated and recorded 28 February 1832, for 38 acres in Scott County from William L. Dulaney to Samuel Strong (ca. 1808-1863).
- Deed, dated 13 March 1834 and recorded 14 March 1834, for land in Scott County from Jonathan W. Morrison, trustee for William L. Dulaney and Edward Campbell, to Samuel Strong.
- Deed, dated 20 April 1839 and recorded 14 May 1839, for 26 acres of land in Scott County from John W. Wompler and others to Thomas Strong, Sr. (ca. 1778-1858).
- Deed, dated 7 October 1842 and recorded 11 October 1842, for land in Scott County from executors of Charles McClung, Sr. (d. 1835), and Charles McClung, Jr. (d. 1828), by their agent, James Francisco, to Thomas Strong.
- Receipt, 4 March 1844, for payment for 560 acres in Logan County, Kentucky from George W. Norton to William Summers.
- Writ, 29 May 1845, issued by the Logan County Circuit Court ordering payment of court costs and fees incurred by conviction of Benjamin Townsend and others to the Bank of Kentucky.
- Deed, dated 10 January 1847 and recorded 24 February 1847, for 200 acres in Scott County from executors of Charles McClung, Sr., and Charles McClung, Jr., by their agent, James Francisco, to Samuel Strong.
- Deed, dated 11 July 1848 and recorded 22 August 1848, for 230 acres in Scott Countyfrom Thomas Strong, Sr., to Samuel Strong.
- Title bond, 10 November 1850, for sale of 300 acres in Washington County, Virginia, from Ota H. Ward to Francis Hogzden.
- Deed, dated 1 October 1855 and recorded 6 November 1855, for 314 3/4 acres in Sullivan County, Tennessee, from Amos James and others to Joseph Latture.